Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Office of the General Executive Board records, 1958-1986 IBT0008
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Office of the General Executive Board Records
1939-1986
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
IBT0008
4.5 Linear Feet
This collection consists of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Office of the General Executive Board records. These range in date from 1958-1986.
Biographical / Historical
The General Executive Board (GEB) of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters (IBT) holds governing authority over the IBT and its subordinate bodies. The Board upholds the laws and policies of the organization as expressed in its Constitution. The number of GEB members has differed over time. The GEB is currently composed of seven At Large Vice Presidents, three Eastern Regional Vice Presidents, five Central Regional Vice Presidents, two Southern Regional Vice Presidents, three Western Regional Vice Presidents, three Canadian Vice Presidents and three Trustees. The GEB meets quarterly to conduct reviews and decide on issues of importance to the Union.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of meeting transcripts and bound minutes and reports pertaining to the General Executive Board. The articles range in date from 1958-1986.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series: Meeting transcripts and Minutes and reports.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, December 5, 2014, (2012.006).
Related Materials
For additional General Executive Board meeting minutes dating from 1907-1908 as well as 1936 please see LAC0004, Reel 11, segment 9 - http://gwdspace.wrlc.org:8180/xmlui/handle/38989/c01wpzhjs.
Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions; Labor and laboring classes; Labor
- Meeting transcripts, 1939-1941, 1958-1959; Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of both transcripts and originals of minutes of various General Executive Board meetings. These minutes are divided into two bulk dates. The first is from 1939-1941 and the second is from 1958-1959.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1939-1940 Minutes Book, Series 1 (Box SHARED box 33, Folder 1)
  - 1940-1941 Minutes Book, Series 1 (Box SHARED box 33, Folder 2)
  - Transcript, 1958 February 10 - 13; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Transcript, 1958 February 10 - 13; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Transcript, 1958 June 30 - July 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Transcript, 1958 June 30 - July 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Transcript, 1958 June 30 - July 1; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Transcript, 1958 September 3-4; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Transcript, 1958 September 15; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Transcript, 1958 September 16; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Transcript, 1958 December 8-13; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Transcript, 1958 December 8-13; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Transcript, 1958 December 8-13; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Transcript, 1959 February 23-27; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Transcript, 1959 June 2-4; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Transcript, 1959 September 28 - October 1; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Minutes and reports, 1976-1986; Series 2
  This series consists of bound minutes and reports from various General Executive Board meetings. These range in date from 1976-1986.
  - General President's Report, 1982, January 19; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - General President's Report, 1982, April 13; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - General President's Report, 1982, July 13; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - General President's Report, 1982, October 29; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - General Secretary-Treasurer's Report, 1982, April 13; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - General Secretary-Treasurer's Report, 1982, January 19; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - General Secretary-Treasurer's Report, 1986, January 21; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Organizing Public Employees Report, 1982, April 13; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Special Meeting, 1976, March 24; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Special Meeting, 1976, June 10; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Special Meeting, 1976, September 14; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Special Meeting, 1977, March 16; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Special Meeting, 1977, September 7; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Special Meeting, 1977, November 10; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Special Meeting, 1979, February 7-8; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Special Meeting, 1979, February 8; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Special Meeting, 1979, March 31; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Special Meeting, 1979, April 10; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Special Meeting, 1979, August 29; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Special Meeting, 1980, November 13; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Special Meetings, 1982, January 28 and March 23; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Special Meetings, 1986, May 16, 18, 20; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1st Meeting, 1976, July 20-21; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1st Meeting, 1981, October 13-15; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 2nd Meeting, 1982, January 19-21; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 2nd Meeting, 1976, October 6-8; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 3rd Meeting, 1977, January 25-27; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 3rd Meeting, 1982, April 13-15; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 4th Meeting, 1982, July 13-15; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 4th Meeting, 1977, April 19-21; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 5th Meeting, 1977, July 6-8; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 6th Meeting, 1977, October 4-6; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 8th Meeting, 1978, January 17-19; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 9th Meeting, 1978, April 18-20; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 10th Meeting, 1978, July 11-13; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 11th Meeting, 1978, October 10-12; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 12th Meeting, 1979, January 16-18; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 13th Meeting, 1979, May 1-3; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 14th Meeting, 1979, July 24-26; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 14th Meeting, 1985, January 15-17; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 15th Meeting, 1979, October 9-12; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 15th Meeting, 1985, April 9-11; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 16th Meeting, 1980, January 22-24; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 17th Meeting, 1980, April 15-17; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 18th Meeting, 1980, July 8-10; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 18th Meeting, 1986, January 21-23; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 19th Meeting, 1980, October 7-9; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 19th Meeting, 1976, January 27-30; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 19th Meeting, 1986, April 29-May 1; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 20th Meeting, 1981, January 29-31; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 20th Meeting, 1976, April 12-14; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)